# **GREGORY T. TOOKES**

HINESVILLE, GA

850-226-1767

GREGORY TOOKES@YAHOO.COM

## PROJECT MANAGEMENT • EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT • SUPPLY / LOGISTICS

#### SUMMARY

Accomplished Project Manager with 20 years of experience within large, diverse organizations. Expertise in managing special operations, emergency controller / operations, and supply / logistics responsibilities. Proven experience in providing critical supplies to personnel performing in 'no room for errors' environments. A natural communicator, effectively liaising at all levels, and across divisions, to lead multifunctional teams toward a common goal. Success derived from application of lessons learned analysis and industry best practices while exceeding goals by utilizing strong work ethic, poise under pressure, and team building abilities. Comfortably leads diverse teams, confident presenting to stakeholders, and has a passion for learning new skills. *United States Air Force veteran*.

Pursuing project leadership role with an organization seeking a trusted professional with logistics, supply, and emergency management experience and a commitment to total customer satisfaction.

### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Project Management Operations Management Stakeholder Engagement Operations Center Leader Emergency Management Risk Management / Mitigation Passenger / Cargo / Supply Shipping / Receiving / Packing Supply / Logistics Management Project Planning – Delivery Maintenance Management After Action Reporting / Briefing

### **CAREER HISTORY**

### WAREHOUSE PACKAGE HANDLER, FEDERAL EXPRESS (FEDEX) - POOLER, GA

2019 - PRESENT

Responsible for the physical loading, unloading, and/or sorting of packages of varying sizes and weights.

- Hand load various freight from different clients and ensure packed in proper trailers for delivery.
- Pick various packages from conveyor line and load on proper trailers.
- Scan various packages from line and hand load packages to trailer going to various locations.

## COMMERCIAL TRUCK DRIVER, KNIGHT TRANSPORTATION – ATLANTA, GA

2015 - 2018

Pick up various types of freight from different shippers and ensure on time, safe delivery to destination.

- Delivers goods while operating a tractor-trailer truck, across intercity routs, and across several states.
- Update company dispatch center of pickup and delivery times, and of freight status.
- Record amount and type of cargo being delivered, and report to dispatch any incidents encountered.

### CLOTHING PACKER (SEASONAL), HUGO BOSS - MIDWAY, GA

2013 - 2014

Worked within fulfillment department, preparing clothing / merchandise to be shipped to various company retail and wholesale outlets.

- Packed clothing to be shipped out to various locations throughout the United States, ensuring proper packaging into appropriate containers, prior to shipping.
- Operates machinery and tools to load packing machinery with garments and packing materials.

## SUPPLY SUPPORT SPECIALIST (TEMPORARY), TAD PDG - FORT STEWART, GA

2013

Provided support to an Army National Guard unit for their required field exercise annual training.

 Set up antennas management, used to maintain location of all army personnel, for the duration of the exercise.

## MERCHANDISING AND PRICING ASSOCIATE (SEASONAL), SEARS — CLEARWATER, FL

2012

Provided customer service and executed marketing and visual programs including display set-up and takedown.

• Performed promotional set-up, replenishment of promotional merchandise, and created visually compelling merchandise displays, fixtures, and store layout.

### SPECIAL OPERATIONS CENTER SUPERVISOR - HURLBURT FIELD, FL

2007 - 2011

Provided command and control leadership of 189 global Special Operations Center personnel and aircraft, including during high operational tempo situations, supporting 1K+ special operations missions.

Gregory T. Tookes Page 2

 Validated, processed and executed joint emergency actions, processing 300+ operational reports annually, and regularly briefed executive stakeholder and headquarters staff on status of special operations aircraft and assets worldwide.

- Focal point for five units across three bases, ensuring quick response to essential messaging.
- Led and enabled successful missions made up of passengers, cargo, and supplies in support of 5.2K missions, including a first-ever CV-22 deployment, ensuring aircraft capabilities were tested and proven in austere conditions.
- Increased operations center efficiency and maintained continuity as a proactive trainer, ensuring professional development and performance excellence within the team.
- Drafted 50 Situations Reports, providing 99% error free situational picture for senior stakeholders.
- Supervised one individual and placed in charge of all shifts worked as a senior controller.

"Focused leader with unsurpassed dedication to the mission! Calm under pressure."

## SENIOR EMERGENCY ACTION MANAGER - SHAW AIR FORCE BASE, FL

2004 - 2007

Provided command and control for Air Combat Command's largest combat fighter division, comprised of three active units.

- Rapidly drafted and transmitted 50 operational reports, sustaining a 98% accuracy rate.
- Tracked 54 cross-country flights, including handling 17 in-flight emergencies, successfully averting aircraft loss and maintaining the division's \$74M flying program.
- Supervised one individual and given responsibility for all shifts worked, as a senior controller.

### SUPPLY TECHNICIAN, SUPPLY DIVISION - SHAW AIR FORCE BASE, SC

1995 - 2004

Responsible for ordering and processing all necessary supplies for maintaining 314 facilities occupied by coalition forces.

- Managed supply inventory valued at \$174K and made up of 168 line items.
- Responsible for managing 1,180 equipment assets valued at \$5M, improving accountability by 100%.
- Led 2-week transfer of Hazardous Material function under single contractor.
- Quickly redeployed a 246-person unit MRSP valued at \$3.5M to support a real-world contingency.
- Managed 86 bench stock accounts consisting of 12,577 line items valued at \$1.25M.

### SUPPLY TECHNICIAN, SUPPLY DIVISION - MOODY AIR FORCE BASE, GA

1987 - 1995

Responsible for storage and maintenance control on 1,823 line items of avionics assets valued at \$6M.

- Processed more than 376 weekly bench stock loads, changes, deletes and transfers, error free.
- Managed a successful waste-buster program that returned 300+ assets per month back into the supply system, saving the Air Force over \$40,000 annually.
- Stored and safeguarded more than 2,900 line items of critical aircraft spares valued at \$12M.
- Performed bi-weekly inventories of recoverable assets in stock, enabling timely identification of errors and correction of inventory imbalances.

### **EDUCATION • CERTIFICATION • TRAINING**

MS, Software Engineering, Colorado Technical University – Colorado Springs, CO BS, Systems Analysis and Integration, DeVry University	2013 2011
AS, Logistics Management, Community College of the Air Force – Shaw AFB, SC	2006
AS, Information Systems Management, Community College of the Air Force – Shaw AFB, SC AS, Business Administration, Georgia Military College	2006 2003
CAPM, Certified Associate in Project Management, PMI	2018

### **TECHNICAL TRAINING**

USAF NCO Academy, Maxwell AFB, AL Command Post Craftsman, Shaw AFB, SC Command Post Apprentice, Keesler AFB, MS Supply Management Craftsman, Lackland AFB, TX Airman Leadership School, Shaw AFB, SC NCO Preparatory Course, Moody AFB, GA

### **PROFICIENCIES AND TRAINING**

Receiving, Flight Service Center, Part Store, Storage and Issue, Customer Service, Bench Stock, equipment Management, Material Readiness Spares Package, Hazardous Material, Furniture Management Office, Proficient with the following in command and control, VHF, UHF, Multitude of COMSEC and other Encryption equipment items, Microsoft OS, and Microsoft Office Suite.